Create an Email Footer
Setup -> Email Administration: Organization-wide email footer -> New.
Setting up Organization-Wide Email Footer for both individuals and mass emails.

Maintain Brand Consistency
Setup -> Communication Templates -> Email Templates
Templates can be set up for Web-to-lead, web-to-case, email-to-case, assignment rules, escalation rules, auto-response rules, workflows.

Create a Folder and Letterhead.
Setup -> Communication Templates: Email Templates -> Create new Folder
									-> Letterheads

Troubleshoot Permissions
Update a profile: People -> Find User, User Profile -> Validate Role: Search for the permission under System Permissions

Automate a Post to Chatter
Lightning Process Builder - allows you to:
	1. Create processes that execute actions when certain conditions are met
	2. Add multiple groups of criteria and associate actions with each criterion.
	3. Create immediate and scheduled actions
	4. Use versioning to easily track and maintain processes.

Supported actions in processes:
	Calling Apex from a process to add a customized functionality to a process.
	Create a new record for any standard or custom object.
	Send an email using the Email Alert action. Note: email alert must be created first.
	Trigger an autolaunched flow to automate complex business processes.
	Post the feed of a user, a Chatter group, or the record that started the process.
	Allow users to use an object-specific or global action to create records, update records, and log calls from the Chatter feed or Salesforce. Note: action must be created first.
	Submit a record through the default approval process or specify a specific approval process.
	Update records or fields on the record that started the process or on any related record including the child records.
	
Considerations for Processes.

Setup -> Create -> Workflows and Approvals -> Process Builder: New 



Create Rules and Time-Based Triggers

Setup -> Create -> Workflows and Approvals ->Workflow Rules -> New Rules 
Add Workflow Action -> New ____ Alert

Workflows


Rule Criteria
Note: Rules are evaluated when a record is created or updated

Workflow Actions:
	Workflow Tasks: Select the subject, status, and priority.
	
	Email Alerts: Select a template.
	
	Field Updates: Select a field.
	
	Workflow Outbound Messages:
	
	Setup -> Time-Based Workflow
	
Creating and Mapping Custom Fields:
	Setup -> Customize -> Leads -> Fields -> Map Lead Fields

Creating Queues
	Setup -> Manage Users -> Queues
	
Creating Assignment Rules
	Setup -> Customize -> Leads -> Assignment Rules
		Note: if a lead does not meet any of the criteria specified in the assignment rule, it will be assigned to the default lead owner.
	Setup -> Customize -> Cases ->Assignment Rules
	
Creating Auto-Response rules
	Setup -> Customize -> Leads -> Auto-Response Rules
	Setup -> Customize -> Cases ->Auto-Response Rules
	
Enabling Web-To-Lead and creating the Web Form: 
	Setup -> Customize -> Object_Name -> Customize Rules
	Setup -> Customize -> Self-Service -> Web-to-Case
	Note: Web-to-Case feature has more template options than Web-to-Lead
	
Order of Execution


