Stuff to learn by the end of the module:


Customize Standard Fields
Standard Fields: 
	Are predefined in Salesforce
	Cannot be deleted
	Can be removed from a page layout
	Can have limited customizations

Types of customizations:
	Changing the field label	Makes the purpose of the fields clearer to users. Below, the Rating standard field label is being changed to make it more convenient for the Sales Operations team to capture the correct data. 
		
		Setup -> Customize -> Tab Names and Labels -> Rename Tabs and Labels
		
		Note: Changes made to the label will only affect what users see in Salesforce and will not affect the fields at the database level. In Setup, the Field Label will still be shown as Rating.
		
		
	Adding help text	Reminds users of the field's purpose and function. Users will see the help text when they hover over the question mark icon.
		
		Setup -> Customize -> Object_Name -> Fields -> Edit
		
	Adding or editing values in picklists	Standard picklist fields contain predefined values.
		
		Setup -> Customize -> Name of Object -> Fields -> Name of Fields
		
	Adding or editing lookup filters	Add and edit lookup filters on standard fields to limit the records available in the lookup.
		
		Setup -> Customize -> Object_Name -> Fields -> Field_Name
		
	Setting field history tracking	Set field history tracking to track and display the field history in the History related list of an object.
		
	Changing the format of auto-number fields	Standard auto-number fields are the unique identifiers for solutions, cases, and contracts. Admins can change the format of these fields.
		
		Setup -> Customize -> Object_Name -> Fields -> Field_Name
		
	
	Create Custom Fields
	Custom Fields allow Salesforce to capture information unique to P66. Custom Fields are allowed to have up to 25 long text area custom fields for each type of record. Deleting a custom field or Changing the Custom Field data type may lose all the data related to the field.
	
	Data loss also deletes list views and assignment and escalation rules.
	
	Within 15 days, you are allowed to undelete a field.
	
	4 Steps to Creating a Custom Field
		1. Choose the Field Type - Same as data type. This depends on the data requirement of the custom field.
		2. Enter the Details - Create a database of the same name. Description is helpful to those who are not familiar with your field.
		3. Establish Field-Level Security - Set access permissions depending on the profile.
		4. Add to Page Layouts - Select the page layouts that should include the new field.
	
	Create Picklists
	Picklists are fields that allow users to select either single or multiple values from a predefined list.
	
	
	Dependent Picklists
	The dependent picklist depends on the data from the controlling picklist.
	Controlling field must be a standard or custom picklist type or a standard or custom checkbox type.
	Dependent field must be a custom picklist or a custom multi-select picklist type.
	
	Global Search for Users - At the top of the search results page, click Search Feeds.
	
	Create Lookups
	Lookup Fields:
	You can link two different objects or link an object to itself to establish a parent-child relationship between the objects. 
	Setup -> Customize -> Search -> Search Settings
	
	Lookup Filters:
	Limits the records available in a lookup field. It can reference:
		Other fields of the same record 
		Fields on the records of the target object
		Fields on the records directly related to the target 
		Fields on the user's record, profile, and role.
		
	Note: Optional lookup filters allow users to save values that don't match the filter criteria.
	
	Dependent Lookups:
	Using a lookup filter that references another field on the same object.
	
	Create a Look Up Filter:
		1. Create a new Backup Agent field
			i. Setup -> Customize -> Cases -> Fields -> Case Custom Fields & Relationships: New 
				1) Lookup Relationship. Related To User.
				2) Field Label - Backup Agent. Field Name - Backup_Agent. Description - blah blah. Help Text - blah blah. Child relationship name - Case.
				3) Show Filter Sections. -> User,  Profile, Name equals Value Support User. Set filter type to Required, and create an error message. Click: Enable this Feature.
				
				
	Test Filter: Tabs: App Launcher -> Call Center -> Cases
	
	Create Formula Fields
	Custom formula fields:
		can be used to build business-specific calculations
		Are read-only fields
		Are not visible on edit pages
		Are supported on standard and custom objects
		Are supported on standard and custom objects
		Can reference standard, custom, or other formula fields
		Cannot reference encrypted, description or custom long text area fields.
	
	Formulas can either be simple or advanced depending on complexity.
	Cross-object formula fields reference fields from parent objects.
	
	Setup -> Customize -> Opportunities -> Fields -> Opportunity Custom Fields & Relationships
	New: Formula
	
	Changing Page Layouts
	What is a page layout?
	It controls the display and organization of detail and allows you to edit pages.
	It controls page section customizations.
	It allows you to set field properties.
	It can be unique for a specific business scenario.
	It can be assigned to a specific profile.
	
	
	
	Setup -> Customize -> Object_Name -> Page Layouts
	
	Page Layout Assignment - Dictates which user profile can view which page layout.
	Holding Shift selects all records in between.
	
	Customize Page Layouts Based on Record Types
	Record types can be assigned to individual users through permission sets.
	Create a Record Type: Setup -> Customize -> Object_Name -> Record Types
	
	Record Types: FAQ 
	Record type used for records created through web-to-case: Cases use the default record type of the default case owner.
	Record type used for records created through web-to-lead: Leads use the default record type of the default lead owner.
	How can a user identify the record type of a record: Admins can add the Record Type field to page layouts.
	Do users always have to select a record type when creating new records: No. Users can choose to always use an object's default record type as set on their profile.
	
	Business processes - 
	Note: you must create at least one business process before you can create a record type for these objects.
	A business process describes the milestones that a record goes through from the time it is 'new' until it is 'done'
	Business processes allow you to:
		Track sales, support, and lead lifecycles across divisions, groups, or markets.
		Associate a business process with one or more record types.
	
	
	
Adding a business process and record type.
Business Process:
	Setup -> Customize -> Opportunities -> Fields -> Field_Label_Name 
	Opportunity Stages Picklist Values -> New
Record Type:
	Setup -> Customize -> Opportunities -> Record Types
	Opportunity Record Type -> New
	
	
	
Maintain Data Quality
History tracking logs for each field. Users can track who made the changes, the date and time of changes, and the old and new values of the changed fields
	Setup -> Customize -> Object_Name -> Fields -> Set History Tracking

System Data Validation: Setting simple field properties to ensure valid data entry.
Custom Validation rules: Allows you to enforce more complex conditions, involving one or more fields. They are only executed.
	Setup -> Customize -> Object_Name -> Validation Rules

Required Fields can be made required through the page layout and are not for picklists or text area.
Unique Fields are self-explanatory

Data Validation Design Methodology: 
	1. State the Business Requirements
	2. Break Down Business Requirements
	3. Express the Error Condition
	4. Compose an error message

Enable Account Field History Tracking (See above)
Create reports after navigating to history tracking: Reports -> Object_Name History Report
	Show all accounts this week -> Run Report

Create an Account/Opportunity Validation Rule (see above)
After navigating to validation rule…
	New -> Enter Formula, error text, then save
	

Customizing Activities
Custom Fields can be created for all activities.
Tasks and events can have validation rules, record types and page layouts.
	Setup -> Customize -> Activities
	
	

