Company Profile is in Setup!
	*Company Information include the following:
	Primary Contact should be the admin's name
	Locale Settings
	Select or deselect notifications from salesforce.com newsletter
	# of user licenses (available, total, and in use)
		Chatter free - users w/out salesforce access have access to Chatter.
		Chatter External - customers have access to Chatter.
	# of feature licenses (available, total, and in use)
		Feature licenses lists the amount of users based on their access type with licenses.

Setting the Fiscal Year and Currency: 
	Setup -> company profile -> company information: Allow Support to Activate Multiple Currencies.
	Setup -> company profile -> fiscal year
	Setup ->Company profile -> manage currencies
			-> new (opens currency type for editing). High conversion rates should be left at 0 for decimal places
			->Edit Rates: allows you to adjust currency rates.
			Note: it  is a good idea to create a dummy opportunity to test currencies. 
	
Modifying User Interfaces
	Setup -> In Build Section: Customize -> User Interface
	Sidebar Settings
	Show Quick Create allows users to quickly complete new Leads, Accounts, contacts and opportunities. If too many records are incomplete, disable this.
	Enable Hover Details gives users a mini record view when they hover over an item in the Recent Items section.
	Enable Collapsible Sidebar allows users to minimize sidebar in order to get more space to view data.
	
	Record Detail Page Settings
	Enable Collapsible Sections
	Enable Hover Details
	Enable Related List Hover Links (hover over links for mini record view)
	Enable Inline Editing (double-click for quick edits)
	
	List View Settings
	Enable Inline Editing (only works if Enabled Lists are enabled as well)
	Enable Enhanced Lists allows for streamlined Chatter view
		By enabling both settings above, users can select and edit multiple records at the same time, navigate easier, and control the number of records per page.
	Enable Printable List Views gives users the option to generate a printer-friendly version of a list view.
	
Setting up Tracking Capability 
	Task vs. Event
	Task = to-do item. Event = calendar event with a duration attached to it. 
	Sales reps should have access to all upcoming and completed items in an activity report to monitor tasks and events.
	
	User Interface Node
	Setup -> Build | Customize -> User Interface
		Enable Home Page Hover Links for Events
		Enable Drag and Drop Editing on Calendar Views - Only works for single user daily calendar views.
		Enable Click-and-Create Events on Calendar Views
			Enable Drag-and-Drop Scheduling on List Views
		Enable Hover Links for My Tasks List
		
	Activity Settings
	Setup -> Customize -> Activities -> Activity Settings
		Show Event Details on Multi-User Calendar View - Read Event details on hover.
		Enable Multiday Events
		Show Requested Meetings in the Calendar Section on the Home Tab
		Show Custom Logo in Meeting Requests
		Allow Users to Relate Multiple Contacts to Tasks and Events - Up to 50 contacts can be related to tasks and events.
		
Configure the Way Users Search
	Salesforce by default displays the first 25 results for each object.
		Min. 5 | Max. 50
	Add up to 10 filters/object
	Up to 10 column.
	
	Search Settings
	Setup -> Customize -> Search -> Search Settings
	Set Results per page under Number of Search Results Displayed per Object section
		Enable "Limit to Items I Own" Search Checkbox - Only shows users their records in search results.
		
	Search Layouts
	Setup -> Customize -> Object (Accounts, Leads, etc.) -> Search Layouts
	Under Action click edit. This is where you add, remove or reorder columns and filters for an object.
	
Create List Views
	Click Object tab -> Create New View
		You can: Save list views for future use,
		filter on specific fields,
		specify which group/s of users have access to the list view, 
		print the list views, or 
		edit records in the list views.
	
Improve Communication 
	Salesforce Chatter allows users to:
		Create private, public, or unlisted (more privacy than private) groups.
			• Each Group has 1 owner, but may have several managers.
			• Owners and managers can invite customers to join the group
			• Unlisted groups only allow members and users with the "Manage Unlisted Groups" permission to access unlisted groups in list views, feeds, and search results. 

Setup Salesforce1
	Mobile setup:
	Setup -> Manage Apps -> Connected Apps
