Import Data (without Data Loader)
Personal Import: My_Name -> My Settings -> Import -> Import My Accounts & Contacs
Organization Import: Setup -> Data Management -> Import <<name of file>>.

Salesforce only accepts .csv files
You need to make sure your data is clean BEFORE importing.
Column headers need to match field names in Salesforce.



When data is imported, the "matching type" needs to be denoted as well. This is the Object for which the data is referencing.

Update Account Data (Data Loader)
Record ID: Copy the record ID from the URLf
Data Loader! Works for standard and custom object.
	Client application
When logging in from an untrusted location, navigate here using a security token:
	My_Name -> My Settings -> Personal -> Reset My Security Token
	


Using Data Loader to export data: 
	1. Login
	2. Get Security Token and paste to the end of password
	3. Select Object to extract.
	4. Name and select a place to save the .csv file
	5. Create the query in Data loader
	6. Export

Update Data Using Data Loader: 
	1. Login
	2. Select Update and select the Object
	3. Click Browse and find the file on the desktop.
	4. Name and select a place to save the successes and errors files.

Create any necessary fields prior to the import
Clean up data prior to import
Export any necessary record ID fields
Prepare and upload a test batch
Do not perform updates to existing records during normal business hours
Turn off workflow rules before running any import, update, or upsert operation

Report on Data.com Capabilities
Data.com DB is…
	Dynamic
	Complete
It can be used to find new records and keep existing records up-to-date.
Key information will be hidden if the user is not assigned a Data.com license. Also, users need a license to add or export records.

Duplicate Management helps maintain clean and accurate data. Depends on duplicate rules.
	Setup -> Data.com Administration -> Duplicate Management


Manage Social Data
Enable Social accounts for each user:
	Setup -> Customize -> Social Apps Integration -> Social Accounts and Contacts -> Settings

Transfer Record Ownership
Mass Transfer records tool allows record transfer based on objects. Related data is transferred to the new owner, and the previous owner, if necessary, needs to be deactivated.

Ensure Regular Backup of Data
You can backup data through reports onto an excel spreadsheet. Data can be automatically loaded onto an excel file. Weekly data exports send an email with the csv files inside a zip file.

Zip files are deleted after 48 hours regardless of whether you downloaded the file.

Setup -> Data Management -> Data Export -> Schedule export -> Set Export Parameters

Delete Bad Data from the Import File
Setup -> Data Management -> Mass Delete Records


The Recycle Bin holds all records for 15 days.

Mass Data Transfer (cont.)
Deactivate User 
Setup -> Manage Users -> Users -> User_Name: Edit -> Deselect "Active" Checkbox.

Data Transfer
Setup -> Data Management -> Mass Transfer Records -> Transfer Account.
Transfer from: Lookup User_Name
Transfer to: Looup User_Name_1
