3 Formats: 
Tabular - simple spreadsheet
	For contact mailing lists and activity reports.
Matrix Format - pivot tables
Summary Format
	Allows for sorting by groups of data.
	
You can freeze the headers: Setup -> Customize -> Reports & Dashboards -> User Interface

Standard Reports
Available out of the box. Must be saved as custom reports bc standard reports cannot be overwritten.

Custom Reports
Must be saved in a custom, personal, or unfiled folder.

All of the following features can be found in the Enhanced Reports Tab
Sort the list by opening the column menu.
Receive Chatter updates by clicking the follow button.
You can use folders to set permissions, but access to folders does not roll up in the role hierarchy.

Enhanced Folder Sharing Model
	- Viewers can see data
	- Editors have editing access
	- Managers have editor access as well as role distribution
Setup -> Customize -> Reports & Dashboards -> Folder Sharing

Fields, Filters and Preview
Drag and drop fields into preview
A matrix report displays data organized in a grid.

Report Filters:
You can add up to 20 filters to a report.

Create a new Report Folder
Reports Tab -> Find a folder…: New Report Folder 

Filter Logic
Add Filters to a report, then click the down arrow, then filter logic. Click OK.

You can type Relative Date Values into the Custom Report Filters.

Adding a Custom Summary Formula to a Report
You can use up to 5 custom summary formulas per report
Cannot reference other summary formulas
Can reference formula fields in the data
Only display on summary rows, not detail (record) rows.

Reports -> Customize -> Formulas: Add formula.

Adding Conditional Highlighting
Reports -> Action (down arrow), Customize -> Show: Conditional Highlighting…

Adding a Chart to a Report
Bar Charts: Each bar represents data from a grouping
	Horizontal bar should compare many groups.
	Vertical bar compares fewer groups when grouping by a date field.
	Also consider: Side-By-Side Bar, Stacked 100% Bar and Stacked Bar.
Line Charts: Each point represents data from a grouping
	Grouping by date field. Great for displaying changes over time.
	Also consider: Grouped Line Chart
Pie/Donut Charts: Each wedge represents data from a grouping.
	Use to compare shares of the grad total. Donuts display the grand total.
Funnel Charts: Each segment represents data from a grouping.
	Use to compare the summarized values of groupings
Scatter Charts: Plot 2 summary fields against each other.
	Visualize the correlation between values in a group.
	Enable the report builder upgrade to use scatter charts.

Schedule and Email a Report
Report -> Select the Report -> Run Report -> Schedule Future Runs… -> Specify the Running User
To me and/or others… -> Select From: Specify User in the search field, Add to Send Email To list.
Select Frequency, Set Start Date and End Date -> Find available options -> Select Time -> Save Report Schedule.

Create custom adoption reports
Reports Tab -> New Report -> Select Report Type -> Create
Use Tabular Format

Building a Dashboard
You can have up to 20 components in one dashboard.
If enhanced folder sharing is turned on, the dashboard is visible to all users.

Create a Dashboard folder in the Reports tab.
	Reports -> New Folder: New Dashboard Folder
	Navigate to that folder
	Share  -> Share with: Group 
	New Dashboard.

Components:
	Tables, Charts, Gauges - Helps show progress towards a goal, Metrics - Uses Conditional Highlighting and displays a single data value drawn from the grand total of a report.

Send Dashboard Component Snapshot:
First enable Dashboard Component Snapshots.
	Setup -> Customize -> Chatter -> Feed Tracking

Specify a running user (user that determines what data users see) in the View dashboard as field.
You can also add filters in a dashboard and use a dashboard as a starting point.

Use Dashboard builder interface.
	Drag a component, a report, edit the component, or select a running user and save.
	
	


