	1. Restrict users from logging into the Salesforce org. for a particular time and location.
	2. Determine the levels of object and record access users should have according to their job roles.
	3. Set up a data access model using a role hierarchy, sharing rules and teams. This is done so users can access the correct records.
	4. Implement record access exceptions to grant special permissions for particular users.
	5. Set user access to calendars and enable sharing
	6. Control field-level access for users so that they have access to the correct fields.

Data Model

	
When a user logs in for the first time, a cookie is placed in their browser and their IP address is added to a trusted list. 
When the user logs in again, Salesforce uses this information for authentication, or it asks the user to activate their computer.
	Activate computer by clicking Email me a verification code to text or email a verification code.


Admins can view which users are logged in using the Session Management tool in Setup and end any suspicious sessions if necessary.

Create a Trusted IP Address List:
Setup -> Security Controls -> Network Access

Restrict Login Hours and Login IP Ranges on Profiles:
Setup -> Manage Users -> Profiles -> Name of Profile -> Login Hours

Setup -> Manage Users -> Profiles -> Name of Profile -> Login IP Ranges
	Set time from 12:00 AM - 12:00 AM if you don't want that user to login 


Object Permissions determine the kinds of records users can view, create, edit, or delete, but not the individual records themselves.

Granting Object Access to Multiple Profiles 
	Enable Enhanced profile list views
		This allows the admin to create a view that lists all profiles so that he can mass update profile permissions instead of updating the profiles individually.
		You can view up to 200 profiles in a single list view and mass update them.
	Setup -> Customize -> User Interface


	Permission Sets are to set temporary permissions for users
		User Access is determined by Profile + any Permission sets assigned to that user.
	Permission sets can only be used to grant additional permissions, not to deny them.
	
	Users must grant login access to the administrator using their My Settings Menu.
	Once access is granted, the admin can log in as the user in the Users list
	Setup -> Users -> Action (Login)
	
	Account Object Permissions View:
		Setup -> Manage Users -> Profiles
		Create a new view. 
	
	Mass Update Delete permissions as per table
		Check all the Profiles you'd like to edit. 
		Double-click the Permission to edit on one of the selected profiles. The image below shows where to click.
		
		
		
	Create a permission set to grant the Account: Delete permission, and assign it to a user
	Setup -> Users -> Permission Set -> New 
		Give relevant Description and Label
		Click Object settings, click the object you'd like to edit, click the permission name under object permissions.
	
	Setup -> Manage Users -> Users -> Hover over Permission Set Assignments -> Edit Assignments. 
	
	Test changes: Setup -> Manage Users -> Users -> Find the user you are looking for -> click Login
	
	Granting Record Access to Multiple Profiles 
	With record-level access within each object, users are able to delete duplicate accounts and contacts by defining an individual account or contact records.
	
	Data Access Model
	A high-level description of a company's data access requirements. It is a useful starting point when determining which records different groups of users will need access to. There are 3 types:
		Public - There are no restrictions on record access. Users can read and edit any record for which they have been assigned the corresponding object permissions on their profile. It is the default model in Salesforce.
		
		Private - Users can only access records they own. They cannot view records owned by other users in reports and search results.
		
		Hybrid - Combination of public and private access. Users can access records they own and records of other users that are necessary for their job function.
		
	Organization-Wide Sharing Defaults
	Private: Access is only given to record owners.
	Public Read Only: Allows all users to view, search, report on all records, and add related records. Only the Records owners can edit these records.
	Public Read/Write: All users can view, edit, search, report on records, and add related records.
	Public Read/Write/Transfer: Allows users to view, edit, search, report on records, add related records, transfer ownership of the record, or delete them. This is only available for lead and case records.
	
	Editing Organization-Wide Defaults
		Setup -> Security Controls -> Sharing Settings -> Edit
	Setting Roles
		Setup -> Manage Users -> Roles -> Set Up Roles -> Expand All -> Add Role
	Assign Users to these Roles
		Setup -> Manage Users -> Roles -> Set Up Roles -> Expand All -> Assign
	You can also delete a role: 
		Setup -> Manage Users -> Roles -> Set Up Roles -> Expand All -> Delete
		
	
	
	
	
	
		
	Exceptions to the Data Access Model
	When the role hierarchy is not flexible enough to deal with all requirements, you will need to manage exceptions. This allows required collaborative access.
	
	Ask yourself:
		1. Share which records (Owned by certain users, Meeting certain criteria)?
		2. With which users (either public groups, roles, or roles and subordinates)?
		3. What level of access (Read-only, read/write)?
	
	Edit Sharing Rules:
		Setup -> Security Controls -> Sharing Settings
	Roles and Subordinates, Roles and Public Groups
	
	Create Public Group:
		Setup -> Manage Users -> Public Groups
	
	Types of Sharing Rules:
	Account Sharing Rule	
	Contact Sharing Rule	
	Opportunity Sharing Rule	
	Case Sharing Rule	
	Lead Sharing Rule	
	Campaign Sharing Rule	
	Custom Object Sharing Rule	
	User Sharing Rule	
	
	Criteria-Based Sharing Rules determine which records to share based on field values in records and can be used for accounts, opportunities, cases, contacts and custom objects. Text and TextArea fields are case-sensitive in sharing rules.
	
	More Exceptions to the Data Access Model
	
	Account Teams: Share roles with the sales teams, Are used for collaborative account management, and are used for sharing and reporting purposes.
	
	Enable the Account Teams setting by navigating to the Account Team Setup page. 
	Setup -> Customize -> Accounts -> Account Teams
		This gives users access to create and use account teams on each account they own.
		When selecting a team member, they can choose the role that a team member plays on the account. Example shown below:
		
	Adding team members and granting access:
		First, log in as the User you would like to  add to the Account Team.
		Next, navigate to Advanced User Details: Name -> My Settings -> Personal -> Advanced User Details.
		Find default account team, and click Add.
		Click Accounts, My Accounts, Go!
		Click corresponding account.
		Hover over Account Team, click Add Default Team.
		
		
		
		
		Screen clipping taken: 8/11/2015 9:42 AM
		
		
	

	Sales Teams:
	
	Team selling feature is mainly informational. It does NOT allow for revenue generated from an opportunity to be divided across members of the sales team.
	
	NOTE: Before setting up Account and Sales teams, the admin needs to first enable account teams or opportunity team selling, and select the page layouts on which the team related lists will appear.
	
	Manual Sharing - Used to grant access on a one-off basis, and can be granted by the owner, any role above the owner, or the administrator.
	
	
	Setting User Access to Calendars
	Provide access to sales reps to view the calendars of other team members, so that while sending invitations for customer calls and meetings, they can check for availability of other team members.
		• Every user has a personal calendar.
	
	Setup Organization-wide access to personal calendars:
		Setup -> Security Controls -> Sharing Settings
		Individuals can grant access to specific users' calendars.
		
	Public Calendars - Administrators and users with the "Customize Application" permission can create public calendars. These calendars can be shared with public groups, roles, and users.
	
	Setup -> Customize -> Activities -> Public Calendars and Resources
	
	
	Manage Field-Level Security
		Field-Level Security defines user ability to view and edit fields in Salesforce, helps enforce data security, and helps ensure that users view only relevant data. Using the field-level security to hide a field from a user also hides the field from list views, search results, and reports.
			Note: Users with edit access to a field will not be able to edit it if they don't also have edit access to the object.
			
		Setup -> Security Controls -> Field Accessibility
		
		Set Opportunity for Field-level Security
		Setup -> Customize -> Opportunities -> Fields -> Click the Field Label, and change the visibility for each record type.
	




Shared With field doesn't cause any changes in rule differences.

