Setting Up and Managing Users

Profile Basics
	Settings vs. Permissions:
		Settings determine how users see the records they have access to.
		Permissions determine what they can do with those records.
		
	Standard profile options:
		System Administrator - "Super User" View and modify all data, customize app.
			Apps, Tabs, Record Types, Page Layouts and Fields can be modified by an Administrator.
		Standard User - View and edit records they can access and delete their own.
		Solution Manager - Standard User + manage published solutions
		Marketing User - Standard User + import leads
		Contract Manager - Standard User + manage contracts
		Read Only - Only view records they can access
		
	Standard Chatter Profiles:
		Chatter Free User - Access to all standard Chatter people, profiles, groups, and files
		Chatter Moderator User - Chatter Free Users + Activate/Deactivate other Chatter Free users/moderators, Grant/revoke moderator privileges, Delete posts and comments they can see.
		Chatter External User - Access groups they've been invited to and interact with members of those groups.
		
	Creating Custom Profiles:
		Setup -> Manage Users -> Profiles -> New
		Delegate Responsibilities to non-administrators by giving them specific permissions for managing users without giving them the broad Manage Users permission.
		
		Enhanced UI:
			Setup -> Customize -> User Interface -> Enable Enhanced Profile User Interface
			With this setting enabled, the profile detail page provides access to all the settings and permissions for a single profile. 
		
		Create new User Profile by cloning the standard user profile:
			Setup -> Manage Users -> Profiles -> New
				• Set Existing profile to the correct Standard Profile option
				• Enhanced Profile List: https://help.salesforce.com/htviewhelpdoc?id=users_profiles_using_enhanced_ui.htm&siteLang=en_US 
				• After User profile has been created, you may designate assigned apps to that User profile
					® Apps - Assigned Apps -> Edit
					® Clear all app permissions
				• System Permissions
					® Same Dropdown as App Permissions
					® Only have the following selected at default
						◊ Edit Events
						◊ Edit Tasks
						◊ Mass Edits from Lists
						◊ Mass Email
						◊ Run Reports
						◊ Send Email
				• You may also set object permissions for the User profile.
					® Drop-down Arrow - Object Settings -> Object_Name -> Edit -> Object Permissions
				• Finally, add the correct personnel to the User profile
					® Setup -> Manage Users -> Users 
					® Find the User, then select Edit -> Profile
			
	User Details:
		Setup -> Manage Users -> Users
		Each User has a license and a user record containing:
			Personal
				- Name, Alias, Email, Phone/Address, Title
			Security & Access
				- Username, License(s), Profile, Role, Login History
			Locale
				- Time Zone, Locale, Language, Currency
		Add Multiple Users allows you to add more than one user at a time.
		Generate New password is selected at default
		
		Create New User: 
			Setup -> Manage Users -> Users
				• Set User License to Salesforce in order to set profile
				• Username must be an email address. 
			
	Chatter Licenses:
		Can be assigned either by creating a new user and selecting the license or by updating Chatter settings that allow other Chatter users to invite external users to Chatter.
		Types of licenses:
		
		Chatter Free License	Users can access people, profiles, groups, and files. They cannot see or interact with Salesforce Data (accounts, contacts, or opportunities)
			
			Also: Make posts, view comments, upload and view files, and join private groups 
		
		Chatter External License	Allows external users to post and share files to the groups they belong to.
			
			Most notably for contractors to access private groups.
		
		Chatter Settings - Coworker Invitations and Customer Invitations
			Coworker Invitations - Assigns a Chatter Free license to the invited user.
				Enable Coworker Invitations by: Setup -> Customize -> Chatter -> Settings.
					Check Allow Coworker Invitations
					Enter P66.com as Company Email Domain.
			Customer Invitations - Assigns a Chatter External license by the invited user. 
				Allows that user to add contractors to a particular group. 
				Users have 30 days to accept a Chatter join invitation. Salesforce user record is automatically created and a Chatter license is assigned.
				
		Create a Chatter Free User - 
			If a new user, set the User License to Chatter Free and the Profile to Chatter Free User
		
		Say hi to a new Chatter user:
			Chatter object -> People -> Person you just added.
			Sample message: 
			"Anonymous, welcome to Chatter. Please upload a photo as soon as you get a chance, and check out the Recommendations to get started."
			
	Login Troubleshooting:
		1. Check User's login history
			i. Setup -> Manage Users -> Users -> Name of User
		2. Ask user to use Forgot your password to recover her password
			i. To reset the user's password for them. Click the check by their name, then select Reset Password(s).
		3. Unlock the account if a password lockout has occurred to reset the password
			i. Setting Password Policies:
				1) Setup -> Security Controls -> Password Policies
				2) To unlock passwords, the Lockout effective period must first be set to Forever (must be reset by admin).
				3) Setup -> Manage Users -> Users -> User's full name -> View Login Attempt History -> Unlock
